<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Virtualbox | neutrofoton]]></title>
  <link href="http://neutrofoton.github.io/blog/categories/virtualbox/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neutrofoton.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-05-10T13:30:13+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://neutrofoton.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[neutro]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu Server Does Not Recognize VirtualBox Adapter]]></title>
    <link href="http://neutrofoton.github.io/blog/2016/10/12/ubuntu-server-does-not-recognize-virtualbox-adapter/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-12T21:25:24+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neutrofoton.github.io/blog/2016/10/12/ubuntu-server-does-not-recognize-virtualbox-adapter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As we know, VirtualBox provides several adapters that we can add and be used by OS guest.
At the time of writing this post, I have an OS X (host) and Ubuntu Server 16.04.1 LTS (guest). The needs are, I want to be able to remote my Ubuntu from OS X terminal. I also want my Ubuntu guest can connect to internet. I have configured two network adapters for the guest (NAT and host-only).</p>

<p>When I run
<code>bash
$ ifconfig
</code>
The first/default adapter (NAT) <code>enp0s3</code> is recognized without any problems by the guest. But not the second one (host-only). To make the second adapter visible, I have to run  a command</p>

<pre><code class="bash">$ sudo dhclient
$ ifconfig
</code></pre>

<p>Now I got both adapters <code>enp0s3</code> (NAT) and <code>enp0s8</code> (host-only) visible on terminal. And now I can ping and run ssh from host (OS X) to guest (Ubuntu server).</p>

<p>In order to make it permanent, we need to edit <code>/etc/network/interfaces</code> with the following lines</p>

<pre><code># The second network interface
auto enp0s8
iface enp0s8 inet dhcp
</code></pre>

<p>Then restart the network service by running</p>

<pre><code class="bash">$ sudo /etc/init.d/networking restart
</code></pre>

<p>That&rsquo;s my note for now and thanks for reading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[VirtualBox Share Host Folder Ubuntu Guest]]></title>
    <link href="http://neutrofoton.github.io/blog/2016/09/17/virtualbox-share-host-folder-ubuntu-guest/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-17T10:41:13+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neutrofoton.github.io/blog/2016/09/17/virtualbox-share-host-folder-ubuntu-guest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/">VM VirtualBox</a> is one of free popular <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypervisor">hypervisor</a> for x86 computer from Oracle. I use it as part of my development environment, since occasionally I need several different Operating Systems for development and software testing  or deployment testing. When we work with VirtualBox we often need to share folder between host and guest operating system.</p>

<p>Before sharing folder, ensure we have installed Guest Addition that shipped with VirtualBox. To do that :</p>

<ol>
<li>Go to  Device menu > Insert Guest CD Addition Images.</li>
<li>If it automatically mounting and has popup dialog, just hit run otherwise we may have to manually mounting it.</li>
</ol>


<p> I usually restart my OS guest after installing this VirtualBox Guest Addition.</p>

<p>The steps are :</p>

<ul>
<li>Go to Devices menu > Shared Folders > Shared Folder Settings</li>
<li>Select folder path of Host to be shared to Guest OS</li>
<li><p>Checked Make Permanent option if we want to make it permanent</p>

<blockquote><p>On my sample, I shared folder from OS X Host /Volumes/MacintoshHDData/share</p></blockquote>

<p> Till this step is enough for Windows guest. On Ubuntu guest, it need additional steps to make the shared folder accessible in guest.</p></li>
<li><p>When we shared a Host&rsquo;s folder on Ubuntu guest, VirtualBox should create a folder on <code>/Media</code> just like the shared folder name with <code>sf_</code> prefix. In my case <code>/Media/sf_share</code>. If the folder does not exist, open terminal, create directory <code>/Media/sf_share</code> and give folder name</p>

<pre><code>mkdir /Media/sf_share
</code></pre></li>
<li><p>VirtualBox with Ubuntu operating system guest, it added a group called <code>vboxsf</code>. Before we can access the shared folder we have to be a member of the group.</p>

<pre><code class="bash">sudo add user [username] vboxsf
</code></pre>

<p> To verify what groups are username belongs to,</p>

<pre><code class="bash">id [username]
</code></pre></li>
<li><p>Mount the shared folder</p>

<pre><code class="bash">sudo mount -t vboxsf share /media/sf_share
</code></pre></li>
</ul>


<p>Now we should be able to the shared folder via Nautilus (File Manager). To make it automatic mounting, ensure we checked option automatic mounting on shared folder setting dialog.</p>

<h2>References</h2>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://askubuntu.com/questions/456400/why-cant-i-access-a-shared-folder-from-within-my-virtualbox-machine">http://askubuntu.com/questions/456400/why-cant-i-access-a-shared-folder-from-within-my-virtualbox-machine</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.howtogeek.com/187703/how-to-access-folders-on-your-host-machine-from-an-ubuntu-virtual-machine-in-virtualbox/">http://www.howtogeek.com/187703/how-to-access-folders-on-your-host-machine-from-an-ubuntu-virtual-machine-in-virtualbox/</a></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
